<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-15T19:09:31-07:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aren Villanueva</title><subtitle>Aren Villanueva's resume, blog and musings on life. Talks about video games like Final Fantasy XIV, software engineering and development, personal finance and early retirement plans and finally self directed trading.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Character</title><link href="/finalfantasyxiv/2019/08/14/my-character.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Character" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/finalfantasyxiv/2019/08/14/my-character</id><content type="html" xml:base="/finalfantasyxiv/2019/08/14/my-character.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;curie-aipella-zalera&quot;&gt;Curie Ai’pella [Zalera]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My character is a female Miqo’te that was created on the Zalera server of the Crystal datacenter.
She was primarily designed by my wife who spent about 30 minutes looking at all the hair styles to pick out the one that she really liked. I ended up changing her hair-style afterwards when I unlocked the hairstylist in-game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/my_character_curie_aipella.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There she is above in Norvrandt.
You can find her profile on lodestone &lt;a href=&quot;https://na.finalfantasyxiv.com/lodestone/character/24219602/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="finalfantasyxiv" /><summary type="html">Curie Ai’pella [Zalera] My character is a female Miqo’te that was created on the Zalera server of the Crystal datacenter. She was primarily designed by my wife who spent about 30 minutes looking at all the hair styles to pick out the one that she really liked. I ended up changing her hair-style afterwards when I unlocked the hairstylist in-game.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Just Arrived</title><link href="/general/2019/08/14/just-arrived.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just Arrived" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/general/2019/08/14/just-arrived</id><content type="html" xml:base="/general/2019/08/14/just-arrived.html">&lt;p&gt;This post is actually quite late considering that I arrived in the pacific north west in January.
Life has been quite busy before and since then and I’ve just finally found time to sit down and actually let out my thoughts.
I think the feeling is similar to arriving at your destination so I named this post accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-this-blog-going-to-be-about&quot;&gt;What is this blog going to be about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve read a lot of advice from other software developers that they really recommend practicing writing.
As a software developer, we do spend a lot of time typing at our keyboards; code, documentation and communication with others.
The content of this blog however is not going to primarily be related to software development or engineering.
I spend a lot of my time playing video games, hiking, exploring and studying finance so these will be prominently written about.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">This post is actually quite late considering that I arrived in the pacific north west in January. Life has been quite busy before and since then and I’ve just finally found time to sit down and actually let out my thoughts. I think the feeling is similar to arriving at your destination so I named this post accordingly.</summary></entry></feed>