<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-24T16:18:09-07:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aren Villanueva</title><subtitle>Aren Villanueva's resume, blog and musings on life. Talks about video games like Final Fantasy XIV, software engineering and development, personal finance and early retirement plans and finally self directed trading.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Mt Rainier</title><link href="/general/2019/08/24/mt-rainier.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mt Rainier" /><published>2019-08-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/general/2019/08/24/mt-rainier</id><content type="html" xml:base="/general/2019/08/24/mt-rainier.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;mt-rainier-sight-seeing&quot;&gt;Mt Rainier sight seeing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Mt Rainier on the 10th of August to hike a few of its trails. We had hoped that the weather would have been clear enough for us to see the mountain in all of its glory but it was unfortunately raining the whole time we were there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;packwood&quot;&gt;Packwood&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started our journey from our accomodation in Packwood, WA. The place we stayed at was a house or cabin in a small corner of the small town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/DSC_0045.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a cosy place that had a pretty nice feel to it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/ufm82sdWTTO1_naqkqHA8g.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The town of Packwood is really quite small. The main town strip has only a handful of stores and a local library that acts as the town center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/packwood.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/packwood_highway.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/packwood_library.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/packwood_elk.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last photo above was an elk that was wandering around town with its pack of females.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mt-rainier&quot;&gt;Mt Rainier&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this town we headed up north towards Mt Rainier and were greeted to more trees and unfortunately rain and fog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/rainier_reflection_lake.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met a lot of Marmots and Chipmunks while hiking around the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/rainier_chipmunks.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;video controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/videos/VID_20190811_153804.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a pleasant experience and I do believe that had there been no rain, it would have been a very colorful and beautiful view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/rainier_flowers.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/rainier_mountains.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/rainier_forest.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/rainier_path.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are definitely going to go back when we get the chance to!
In the future, we’ll be planning on visiting Mt Baker and getting some nice hikes and photography happening over there too so keep an eye on my blog and hopefully it will pop up!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">Mt Rainier sight seeing I went to Mt Rainier on the 10th of August to hike a few of its trails. We had hoped that the weather would have been clear enough for us to see the mountain in all of its glory but it was unfortunately raining the whole time we were there.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Melbourne Vs Seattle</title><link href="/general/2019/08/15/melbourne-vs-seattle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Melbourne Vs Seattle" /><published>2019-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/general/2019/08/15/melbourne-vs-seattle</id><content type="html" xml:base="/general/2019/08/15/melbourne-vs-seattle.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;melbourne-vs-seattle&quot;&gt;Melbourne vs Seattle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very subjective piece as it is about my own personal experience between the two cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-upbringing&quot;&gt;My upbringing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was raised between the ages of 4 to 27 in the western suburbs of Sydney, New South Wales, Australia. Where I lived was a very working class, blue collar demographic area that was slowly gentrifying. It is still gentrifying, the odd times I visited after moving away I would find myself in newly built estates, revamped shopping centers and a younger vibe to the urban areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family was not a wealthy one. We struggled to make ends meet at times and my mother was introduced to gambling by a friend. The gambling became an obsession and we eventually lost the family home when we could no longer find anybody willing to help us. It was here that my attitude towards my personal and professional life was shaped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved out of my parents home to the north shore area of Sydney. Wealthy inhabitants were and still are plenty in those suburbs and by living around them and interacting with them often helped me see what it was like outside of the bubble that I once lived in. The people I met were generous with their time and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-to-melbourne-victoria&quot;&gt;Moving to Melbourne, Victoria&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I relocated to Melbourne at the age of 28 after landing a position at Iloura. I met my now wife there and found that I really did not like Melbourne. I wasn’t able to succintly point what bothered me until a few years had gone by. Thinking through the interactions and close observations of the people living there I could finally point out the underlying problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of selfish people in Melbourne and the culture of Melbourne subconciously promoted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When commuting by car there was never a day where I didn’t see a super aggressive driver. Weaving around traffic impatiently, suddenly changing lanes to try and beat the queue by a car or two. Often times I’d find myself keeping up with these drivers even as I stayed in the same lane and just dealt with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of Porsche driving around were ridiculous. It seemed like everyone and their mother was driving around in a Porsche Cayenne. Compare this to my time living in the northern shores of Sydney where I may have seen 1 Porsche in a 6 month period. There’s this culture of excess in Melbourne and a lot of “new money” that are keeping up with the Jones’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The well known saying of “I’ve got mine, fuck you” really describes what a lot of Melbourne was like for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say that everyone in Melbourne was like that, and I’ve been careful in my words in this article to never deal in absolutes. We have great friends living in Melbourne and great memories of the City and the state of Victoria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transplanting-to-seattle&quot;&gt;Transplanting to Seattle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I moved to Seattle in January of this year. We have loved it. Even before we landed there was this at-home feeling that came over me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seattle has its problems; most prominent being the homelessness. What really strikes me, and what reminds me of my upbringing was the indifference everyone has of each other. People don’t care about what I wear, how I look, who I am. They also don’t care about what I think of them and it shows. I see every day, people from different walks of life wearing whatever they like, looking whatever they like and its great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also a less populated city compared to Melbourne or Sydney. To me it has this nice big town, little city kind of feel to it that reminds me of Adelaide, South Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve read about the famous Seattle freeze and quite frankly, for my wife and I it’s a blessing. We’re somewhat introverted and we’re not from families or cultures that emphasize making friends with strangers. We’ll see how we go over the next few months and years to see if our opinion of Seattle changes but so far we’ve not had anything that would indicate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad that we moved to Seattle. Should it come to pass that we needed to return to Australia, Melbourne would probably be the last place we would move back to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">Melbourne vs Seattle This is a very subjective piece as it is about my own personal experience between the two cities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Just Arrived</title><link href="/general/2019/08/14/just-arrived.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just Arrived" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/general/2019/08/14/just-arrived</id><content type="html" xml:base="/general/2019/08/14/just-arrived.html">&lt;p&gt;This post is actually quite late considering that I arrived in the pacific north west in January.
Life has been quite busy before and since then and I’ve just finally found time to sit down and actually let out my thoughts.
I think the feeling is similar to arriving at your destination so I named this post accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-this-blog-going-to-be-about&quot;&gt;What is this blog going to be about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve read a lot of advice from other software developers that they really recommend practicing writing.
As a software developer, we do spend a lot of time typing at our keyboards; code, documentation and communication with others.
The content of this blog however is not going to primarily be related to software development or engineering.
I spend a lot of my time playing video games, hiking, exploring and studying finance so these will be prominently written about.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html">This post is actually quite late considering that I arrived in the pacific north west in January. Life has been quite busy before and since then and I’ve just finally found time to sit down and actually let out my thoughts. I think the feeling is similar to arriving at your destination so I named this post accordingly.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Character</title><link href="/finalfantasyxiv/2019/08/14/my-character.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Character" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/finalfantasyxiv/2019/08/14/my-character</id><content type="html" xml:base="/finalfantasyxiv/2019/08/14/my-character.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;curie-aipella-zalera&quot;&gt;Curie Ai’pella [Zalera]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My character is a female Miqo’te that was created on the Zalera server of the Crystal datacenter.
She was primarily designed by my wife who spent about 30 minutes looking at all the hair styles to pick out the one that she really liked. I ended up changing her hair-style afterwards when I unlocked the hairstylist in-game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;singular-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.villanueva.dev/images/my_character_curie_aipella.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There she is above in Norvrandt.
You can find her profile on lodestone &lt;a href=&quot;https://na.finalfantasyxiv.com/lodestone/character/24219602/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="finalfantasyxiv" /><summary type="html">Curie Ai’pella [Zalera] My character is a female Miqo’te that was created on the Zalera server of the Crystal datacenter. She was primarily designed by my wife who spent about 30 minutes looking at all the hair styles to pick out the one that she really liked. I ended up changing her hair-style afterwards when I unlocked the hairstylist in-game.</summary></entry></feed>